[English subtitles are available]
[Programa con subtítulos en español]
[Road Home]
[Camino a Casa]
[Episode 5]
[Episodio 5]
I'm going to buy something.
Voy a comprar algo.
It's dirty inside. I haven't cleaned up yet.
Está sucio adentro. No lo limpié.
It's okay.
No pasa nada.
Go inside and watch the film.
Ve a ver una película.
I'll take it to you
Cuando tenga la comida lista,
when I'm done.
te la traeré.
I want to see you cook.
Quiero verte cocinar.
I've never seen it before. I'm curious.
No lo he visto. Tengo curiosidad.
You are curious about everything.
Tienes curiosidad por todo.
Wait a minute.
Entonces espera.
I'll clean up.
Déjame ordenar un poco.
I've bought you some barbecue.
Te compré una barbacoa.
Eat it yourself.
Ve a comer.
Okay, got it.
Vale, lo sé.
It's so spicy.
¡Qué picante!
Do you want some?
¿Te dejo un poco?
No, I don't like it.
No, no me gusta.
I just finished it.
Justamente he terminado todo.
In what way do you want to cook?
¿Cómo quieres hacerlas?
What do you want to eat?
¿Cómo quieres comerlas?
Egg them before deep-frying.
Vamos a freírlas en una envoltura de huevo.
Don't you think it's troublesome?
Qué complicado.
It isn't me doing it anyway.
De todos modos, no lo hago yo.
You're here.
Hola.
Wait in the room.
Espera adentro.
No.
No.
I just want to watch you work here.
Solo quiero verte trabajar aquí.
The workshop is too cold.
El taller está muy frío.
No need to wipe.
No hace falta.
I'll wash it myself.
Lo lavaré yo misma.
I'm leaving first. Hurry up.
Me voy primero. Rápido.
I didn't mean it.
No lo vi a propósito.
I just want to see the ending.
Solo quise ver el final.
Get ready to eat.
Ordena un poco y vamos a comer.
Don't watch these anymore.
Mira menos este tipo de cosas en adelante.
You should study hard.
Dedes estudiar con esfuerzo.
I didn't know they'd have the scene.
No sabía que iba a mostrarme esto.
Remember to call me.
Recuerda llamarme.
Last semester,
El semestre pasado,
you had underperformance.
te comportaste muy mal.
I often couldn't contact you.
A menudo no pude encontrarte.
There was a lot of training
Tengo muchos entrenamientos.
and only a few training places with a strong signal.
Y en pocos lugares hay señal.
I know.
Lo sé.
Call me
De todos modos, si no estás ocupado,
whenever you are unoccupied.
llámame.
[In the year 2010]
[2010]
[In the year 2020]
[2020]
You are...
¿Estás...?
Has your first love
¿Ha vuelto
back yet?
tu primer amor?
I want to see him.
Quiero verlo.
Probably no.
No.
What do you mean by probably no?
¿Cómo que no?
Haven't you asked him?
¿No lo preguntaste?
The kid is with you.
Puso su hijo aquí.
Shouldn't you two
Entonces ustedes dos
chat three times a day?
tienen que comunicarse tres veces al día.
He has a special occupation.
Su profesión es especial.
Sometimes, he disappears for a few days.
Suele desaparecerse por unos días.
How can I chat with him always?
¿Cómo podemos comunicarnos a tiempo?
And if he comes back,
Además, si vuelve,
I think he will inform me.
me lo diría.
Long time no see.
Cuánto tiempo.
You're still the same.
Como siempre.
Nothing good happens when I see you.
No pasa nada bueno al verte.
You're in your thirties,
Ya tienes más de treinta años,
but still, act like a teenager.
sigues comportando como un adolescente.
Is it fun?
¿Es interesante?
You're back.
¿Has vuelto?
Minshan, you are here.
Minshan, estás aquí.
Aunt.
Señora.
Come here.
Ven, ven.
Come and sit here.
Ven a sentarte aquí.
How did you get here?
¿Cómo viniste?
My dad sent me here.
Mi padre me trajo aquí.
Where is your dad?
¿Y tu padre?
He has a dinner party tonight.
Tiene una cena esta noche.
So he didn't have time
No tiene tiempo
to visit you.
para subir a saludarle.
No need.
No hace falta.
He doesn't have to bother visiting me.
No hace falta que me salude.
Lu Chen, get Minshan a glass of water.
Chen, sírvele a Minshan un vaso de agua.
Mum, I'm leaving.
Mamá, me voy primero.
Sister will be here soon.
Mi hermana vendrá más tarde.
I'm talking to you.
Estoy hablando contigo.
Aunt.
Señora,
He came to accompany you overnight
bajó del tren
after getting off the train.
y vino a acompañarte toda la noche.
Let him go back and rest early.
Déjalo volver y descansar temprano.
Speak it out.
Dímelo si tienes dudas.
What's your relationship
¿Qué relación tienes
with Zhao Minshan?
con Zhao Minshan?
Could you even be together at such a far distance?
Pueden contactarse incluso ya están tan lejos.
I don't think so.
¿Cómo es posible?
I'm a little tired.
Estoy un poco cansado.
I don't want to talk.
No quiero hablar.
I heard that
He oído que
Zhao Minshan had just divorced not more than two years.
Zhao Minshan acababa de divorciarse hace unos años,
Be careful.
ten cuidado.
She is
Ella
very scheming.
tiene muchas intrigas.
She screwed me up.
Antes fui engañado por ella como idiota.
You disappointed Meng Xiaoshan
No soportaste la tentación
because you couldn't stand the temptation.
y por eso fallaste a Meng Xiaoshan.
Yes, you're right.
Sí, tienes razón.
I can't blame others.
No es culpa de los demás.
It's my fault.
Es mi culpa.
[Lu Zheng Automobile Repair]
[Taller de automóviles Lu Zheng]
You're back.
Has vuelto.
Uncle Liu is dirty.
Tengo la ropa sucia.
I've accustomed to it when I was young.
Me acostumbré cuando era niño.
Okay.
Bien.
Let's go out and eat.
Vamos a comer fuera.
Everybody is going together.
Todos vayan.
It's on Uncle Liu's treat today.
Hoy es mi trato.
Haidong, let's go together.
Haidong, ven con nosotros.
Okay, Uncle Liu.
Vale, Sr. Liu.
Let's go.
Vamos.
Is everything good in Qining?
¿Estás bien en Qining?
Are you coming back for getting married?
¿Esta vez regresas para casarte, no?
Who is he marrying?
¿Con quién?
Could it be
¿Acaso
his girlfriend who's in Qining?
tu novia en Qining?
You didn't even tell me.
No me lo dijiste.
I'm not planning to get married.
No quiero casarme.
Will your dad allow you
¿Tu padre te perdonará
not listening to him?
si no le escuchas?
What happened exactly?
Pero, ¿qué pasó?
Who can let me in on it?
¿Quién me lo explica?
It's Lu Chen's father.
El padre de Luchen
He'd borrowed more than one million
le pidió prestado durante estos años
from the Zhao family
más de un millón a la familia Zhao.
and couldn't pay it back.
Y ahora no pudo hacer la devolución.
Later, the daughter of the Zhao family
Luego, la hija de la familia Zhao
said,
dijo que,
"How about this?
sería mejor que
We can become in-laws.
se casara con su hijo,
You don't have to pay back the money."
de esta manera no sería necesario devolver el dinero.
The daughter also said,
La hija dijo también que
"Lu Chen and I
ella y Chen
are old classmates.
eran viejos compañeros.
We know each other well.
Se conocían muy bien.
I'm willing to marry him."
Estaba dispuesta a casarse con él.
Zhao Minshan?
¿Zhao Minshan?
Did you also hear about it?
¿También lo has oído?
I figured it out.
Lo adiviné.
But Lu Chen,
Pero, Chen,
now,
ahora
you don't have to be afraid of your dad.
no tienes que temer a tu padre.
He's old now.
Ahora ya está viejo.
Maybe
Tal vez
he won't be able to punish you anymore.
no te puede hacer nada.
But you can't
Pero esta deuda
welch on the debt.
no se puede negar.
You are his son.
Eres su hijo.
If you don't pay his debt,
Si no le pagas la deuda por él,
he will force your elder sister to pay it back.
tiene que obligar a tu hermana a pagar.
Am I right?
¿Verdad?
Enough.
Ya, ya.
Lu Chen just came back.
Luchen acaba de volver.
Let's talk about something cheerful.
Hablemos de algo feliz.
Come on.
Venga.
Okay.
Bien.
Let's eat.
Comamos, comamos.
There's always a solution.
Siempre hay una solución.
Qin Xiaonan.
Qin Xiaonan.
Just put your clothes there.
Pon la ropa allí.
I'll wash them together later.
La lavaré luego.
No, I'll do it myself.
No, puedo lavarla yo mismo.
Do you like washing clothes so much?
¿Te gusta tanto lavar la ropa?
Then help me
Entonces ayúdame
wash mine too.
a lavar la mía también.
Just kidding.
Es una broma.
It's okay.
No pasa nada.
Take your clothes to me.
Tráemela.
I'll wash them for you.
Te ayudo a lavarla.
I don't dare to slave you.
No me atrevo a esclavizarte.
I'm serious. Just put them there.
Lo digo en serio, déjala ahí.
If you
Si
feel sorry to trouble me,
no quieres pedirme la ayuda,
I'll wash them
luego
with a washing machine.
la lavaré con la lavadora.
It can be dried too. How awesome it is!
También se puede secar. ¡Qué bien!
I'm on a business trip the day after tomorrow.
Estaré de viaje de trabajo pasado mañana,
I may not be able to
no podré
take care of Qin Xiaonan.
cuidar de Qin Xiaonan.
Come pick him up if you have come back.
Si regresas, ven a recogerlo.
If not...
Si aún no regresas...
Who should take care of him?
¿Quién puede ayudar a cuidarlo?
It's usually not a big deal.
Normalmente es fácil de decidir.
But now the Chinese New Year is around the corner.
Pero se acerca el Festival de Primavera.
It's inappropriate to place him at anyone's house.
No es apropiado dejarlo en cualquier familia.
We'll see.
Ya veremos.
Speak it out.
Dime.
What have you been doing recently?
¿Qué estás haciendo últimamente?
After the class reunion,
No te vi después
we have no chance to hang out with you at all.
de la reunión de compañeros.
I'm working.
Estoy trabajando,
What else can I do?
¿qué más puedo hacer?
I got something to share with you.
Tengo algo que decirte.
I heard that
Acabo de oír que,
Zhao Minshan,
Zhao Minshan
who had divorced two years ago...
se divorció hace dos años, ¿no?
It was a hearsay, Gui Xiao.
Me enteré de otras personas, Gui Xiao.
I heard that
Me enteré de otras personas.
Chen had just returned
Chen acaba de regresar
two days ago.
hace dos días, ¿no?
They are getting married.
Los dos van a casarse.
Who?
¿Quién?
Chen.
Chen.
I remember when Chen came back last time,
Pienso que la última vez cuando Chen regresaba,
you came to call on him.
lo buscaste,
So I'm telling you the news.
así que vine a decírtelo.
Is Lu Chen back?
¿Chen ha vuelto?
♫My unbosoming no longer attracts you♫
♫Ya no sientes nada sobre mis palabras♫
Yes.
Sí.
He came back yesterday.
Volvió ayer.
I didn't expect
No esperaba que
our campus beau to be
Zhao Minshan lograra
obtained by Zhao Minshan.
el galán de nuestra escuela secundaria.
♫How much indifference do I get for holding on?♫
♫Cuánta frialdad puedo cambiar con el aguante♫
Also,
Además,
the Zhao family is ready for a wedding.
la familia Zhao ya está preparando la boda.
They have booked the restaurant
El restaurante que reserva
♫Good night that I can't text♫
♫El mensaje de buenas noches que no se envió♫
managed by Meng Xiaoshan.
es lo de Meng Xiaoshan.
Aren't you familiar with Meng Xiaoshan?
¿No conoces bien a Meng Xiaoshan?
Ask her.
Pregúntale a ella.
She must know better than me.
Debe saberlo mejor que yo.
♫I used to believe that hard efforts would leave no regrets♫
♫Antes creía que el esfuerzo no dejaba arrepentimientos♫
I have to go.
Te dejo.
♫But the situation has come to a head♫
♫Pero el resultado es demasiado malo♫
Let's talk later.
Hablemos más tarde.
Okay, bye.
Bueno, adiós.
♫Who's going to bear for me?♫
♫Quién asumirá la responsabilidad por mí♫
Happy New Year in advance.
Te deseo feliz año nuevo con anticipación.
Happy New Year.
Feliz año nuevo.
♫We said it would last forever♫
♫Acordamos para siempre♫
♫But we were separated in the end♫
♫Pero finalmente nos separaremos♫
♫I wait until I give up all resistance♫
♫Espera a que baje lentamente la resistencia♫
♫Let time pass by♫
♫Dejo que el tiempo fluya♫
♫Never thought that love♫
♫Nunca pensé que el amor no es♫
♫Is not about the trials and tribulations♫
♫tan simple como♫
♫That simple♫
♫pasar las dificultades♫
♫We wait until there's a twist in the plot♫
♫Esperamos a que la situación cambie♫
♫We still keep our hopes up♫
♫Todavía tenemos esperanza♫
♫With your absence, I stand in♫
♫Estoy de pie en la noche donde no estás♫
♫The nights when I can't even shed a tear♫
♫Una noche sin lágrimas♫
♫The street lights on the corner pass by dimly♫
♫La luz de la calle, la oscuridad que pasé♫
♫It's too late♫
♫Todo es demasiado tarde♫
I heard you went back to Beijing.
Oí que habías vuelto a Beijing.
He just asked me to do him a favour.
Solo me pidió una ayuda.
I agreed and it's already done.
Lo acepté y lo hice.
It should be over.
Todo debe acabarse.
Don't give it too much thought.
No debo pensar demasiado.
He didn't say anything.
No ha dicho nada.
Hello?
Aló.
Sorry, Gui Xiao.
Lo siento, Gui Xiao.
Something urgent came up at home.
Esta vez tengo algo urgente en mi familia.
I'm back for two days.
Vuelvo a casa por unos días
But I had a busy schedule.
y no tengo tiempo para otras cosas.
It's okay.
No pasa nada.
I'm leaving Beijing the day after tomorrow.
Me iré de Beijing pasado mañana y
The Chinese New Year is coming.
se acerca el Festival de Primavera.
It's not suitable
No es conveniente dejar el niño
to leave the kid to my friends.
a mis amigos.
I heard you were back.
Dicen que has vuelto.
So I wanted to ask you when you will be free
Así que quiero preguntarte cuándo te conviene
to pick up the kid.
para recogerlo.
The day after tomorrow.
¿Pasado mañana?
How about I just drive him there?
¿Qué tal si te lo llevo en coche?
I'll go tomorrow.
Vendré mañana.
It's a deal.
Quedamos así.
Thank you.
Gracias.
No problem.
De nada.
I can help you.
Justamente puedo ayudarte.
Lu Chen.
Luchen.
I'm saving money.
Estoy ahorrando dinero.
I'll visit you when I have enough money.
Iré a verte cuando tenga suficiente dinero.
One more minute, okay?
Un minuto más, ¿de acuerdo?
Do you miss me?
¿Me extrañaste?
Can't you say more?
¿No puedes decir más?
Don't we
¿No tenemos
speak the same language?
temas comunes?
I'm now living on campus.
Me he alojado en la residencia escolar.
I'm so torn.
Te digo que estoy muy indecisa.
There are four people in our dorm.
Hay cuatro personas en nuestro dormitorio.
I don't know if I can get used to it.
No sé si puedo acostumbrarme.
Oh no.
Oh, no.
My mum knows who you are.
Mi madre ya sabe quién eres.
Recently,
Últimamente,
I can't answer the phone at home.
no puedo contestar el teléfono en casa.
Don't call me.
No me llames.
Wait for my call.
Te llamaré.
Lu Chen.
Luchen.
Bye.
Cuelgo.
It's winter.
Es invierno.
Why didn't you close the door and block the wind?
¿Por qué no cierras la puerta para evitar el viento?
Why are your eyes red?
¿Por qué tus ojos están rojos?
Did you quarrel with your dad?
¿Peleaste con tu padre?
No.
No.
I recall the past.
Me acordé del pasado.
The past?
¿El pasado?
Isn't your past all about Gui Xiao?
Tu pasado es Gui Xiao, ¿no?
What could you recall?
¿Qué recordaste?
Why did you break up?
¿Por qué rompieron?
I still haven't figured it out yet.
Todavía no lo entiendo.
Look, when I broke up with Meng Xiaoshan,
Mira, rompí con Meng Xiaoshan.
it's my fault.
Es mi culpa.
What about you two?
¿Y ustedes dos?
It's my fault.
Fue mi culpa.
At that time,
En ese momento,
she was a girl.
era una chica.
She put all her emotions
Ponía todas las emociones
on the phone call.
en una línea telefónica.
She couldn't see or touch them.
No podía ver ni tocar.
How pitiful.
¡Qué pobre!
Actually, during that period,
En realidad,
when I couldn't see her,
yo no podía verla,
I missed her too.
pero también la extrañaba.
I missed her so much.
La extrañaba mucho.
Every time I hear her calling me Lu Chen,
Cada vez que la escuchaba llamarme Chen,
and calling my name on the phone,
me llamaba por teléfono,
I feel that she has the most pleasant voice
yo creía que era la voz más bonita
in the world.
en el mundo.
Every time.
Cada vez.
Enough. Stop it.
Basta, basta.
You make me feel sad.
También lo lamento.
Normally,
A la edad normal,
she should have gotten married.
ella debería estar casada.
Her children should be teens ages.
y sus hijos no deberían ser muy pequeños.
Where are you going?
¿Adónde vas?
Take a shower.
A ducharme.
Shower? It's Chinese New Year.
¿Ducharte? Es Año Nuevo.
There's no heater in your bathroom.
No hay calefacción en tu baño.
Do you want to be frozen to death?
¿Quieres morir de frío?
I've even taken a bath in the snow in Qining.
Me duché con nieve en Qining.
I'm not afraid of the cold.
Lo que menos me da miedo es el frío.
I'll fix the car.
Voy a reparar el coche.
He dismantles the car
Este chico,
every time he feels sad.
al sentirse triste, deshará coches.
It never changes.
Nunca cambia.
I came here with only one bag of stuff.
Cuando vine, solo tenía una bolsa de cosas.
But I'm leaving with this much.
Cuando me voy, tengo tanto,
My dad will scold me.
mi padre va a regañarme.
Not much at all.
No tanto.
These are
Estos son
for you to wear
de la cantidad que utilizarás
in school later.
y te vestirás en la escuela.
You're going to see Uncle Lu soon.
Vas a ver al Sr. Lu.
Are you happy?
¿Estás contento?
Yes.
Sí.
I wonder if the repair shop
No sé si se puede alojarse
is still accommodable.
en ese taller de automóviles en mal estado.
What a waste.
Es un desperdicio.
These slippers are so small.
Estas zapatillas son tan pequeñas,
Who will wear them in the future?
¿para quién se las pondrá en el futuro?
Little wordy. Let's go.
Chiquito, vamos.
Here.
Ven.
Aunt Gui Xiao, is this the place?
Señora Gui Xiao, ¿es aquí?
We're here.
Sí.
Here we are.
¿Ya llegamos?
So spacious!
¡Qué grande!
It's larger than I thought.
Es más grande de lo que yo imaginaba.
Hello, I'm looking for Lu Chen.
Hola, busco a Chen.
Wait, miss.
Espera, señorita.
I'll make a call.
Haré una llamada a los de dentro.
It's cold outside. Come in first.
Hace frío afuera. Entra.
Come on, kid.
Ven, el niño también.
Okay, thank you.
Vale, gracias.
Let's go.
Vamos.
Someone is looking for Lu Chen. At the door.
Alguien está buscando a Chen, está a la puerta.
A girl and a kid.
Una chica y un niño.
Miss, he'll come out now.
Señorita, viene ahora mismo.
Does this factory all belong to Uncle Lu?
¿Todo este taller es del Sr. Lu?
Yes.
Sí.
Uncle Lu.
Sr. Lu.
Is it new-bought?
¿Es nueva?
He had too much stuff to fit.
Tiene tantas cosas que no cabía,
So I bought him a new one.
así que compré una nueva.
I won't go in further.
No voy a entrar.
Come.
Ven.
Come inside and have a seat.
Entra y siéntate.
Where is the toilet?
¿Dónde está el baño?
The right side.
A la derecha.
It's cold in the factory.
Hace frío en el taller.
Don't take off your coat first.
No te apresures a quitarte la chaqueta.
I'll leave after a few words.
Me iré después de unas palabras.
I've found a private school
La escuela privada para Qin Xiaonan
for Qin Xiaonan.
está decidida.
I'll be away for a long time.
Mi viaje de negocios durará mucho tiempo.
But I'll ask my cousin
Pero pediré a mi primo
to take you to school.
que les lleve a la escuela a hacer la matrícula.
I bought some clothes for him.
Le compré ropa.
From now on,
En el futuro,
you should also buy him some clothes every year.
también tienes que comprarle ropa cada año.
But not too many.
No necesitas comprar mucho.
He can wear school uniforms usually.
Habitualmente tiene uniforme escolar.
That's all.
Eso es todo.
Do you still love me?
¿Todavía me amas?
Bai Chao said that
Bai Chao dijo que
you were getting married.
te casarías.
Lu Chen?
Chen.
Yes.
Sí.
When?
¿Cuándo?
Next month.
El próximo mes.
♫Do you hear?♫
♫Has oído♫
♫Several years♫
♫Durante tantos años♫
Congratulations.
Felicidades.
♫Ask from my soul over all desire♫
♫Las expectativas provenientes del fondo de mi alma♫
♫Feel your heart♫
♫El corazón vacío♫
♫Heal your wound♫
♫La herida curada♫
♫Wait for your return, overcome the fear♫
♫Está esperando a que tu corazón supere la inquietud♫
Aunt.
Señora.
Uncle Lu is getting married.
El Sr. Lu se va a casar,
He'll be quite busy.
estará muy ocupado.
Remember
Lo que te dije en el coche
what I told you in the car.
también tienes que recordar tú mismo.
Also,
Además,
if you are neglected at school,
si te ignoran en la escuela,
remember what Aunt Gui Xiao said.
recuerda lo que te dije.
All transfer students
Todo los alumnos que transfieren a una escuela nueva
will go through this process.
sufrirán este proceso.
They'll accept you after a long time.
Te aceptarán después de mucho tiempo.
Aunt.
Señora.
Go on with your work. I'm leaving.
Sigue con tu trabajo. Me voy.
Wait.
Espera.
How much is the suitcase?
¿Cuánto cuesta la maleta?
One hundred.
Cien.
Here's for Xiaonan's clothes
Por la ropa de Xiaonan,
and his living cost of staying at your house for days.
y los días que se ha alojado en tu casa,
Thank you.
mucha gracias.
Lu Chen.
Chen.
You don't have to be so calculative.
No tienes que calcularlo tan claramente.
You helped me in Qining.
También me ayudaste en Qining.
Lu Chen.
Chen.
Why are you not coming out? There're guests outside.
No sales aunque te llame. ¿Tienes visitantes?
You...
Eres...
Gui Xiao.
Gui Xiao.
Do you still remember me?
¿Me recuerdas?
I'm Zhao Minshan from Class 2.
Zhao Minshan de la clase 2.
Long time no see. You've been prettier.
Cuánto tiempo sin verte. Te has vuelto más guapa.
I nearly
Casi
couldn't recognize you.
no la reconocí.
Are you
¿Tú eres
the friend Lu Chen's mother mentioned?
la amiga que dijo la madre de Chen?
I heard from Mrs Lu that
Me dijo ella que
he had a friend coming today.
vendría una amiga de él hoy.
Since he has been outside
Pienso que durante tantos años
all these years,
no vive aquí.
I've never seen
A sus amigos
those of his friends.
nunca he visto.
So I came out
Por eso quiero salir
to have a look.
para echar un vistazo.
I didn't expect that it was you.
No pensaba que fueras tú.
What a coincidence.
¡Qué casualidad!
Is this your kid?
¿Tu hijo?
It's his comrade's.
Es de su compañero.
He asked me to go through the school procedure for him.
Me pidió que hiciera el traslado de escuela.
Lu Chen never mentioned it.
Chen no lo mencionó.
I've sent the kid here.
El niño está aquí.
I'm leaving first.
Me voy.
Please don't go.
No te vayas.
Stay here and have lunch with us.
Quédate a almorzar.
Oh, Lu Chen.
¡Chen!
She came through a far way.
Viene desde muy lejos,
How could you not invite her for a meal?
¿por qué no la pides quedarse a comer?
No need.
No, no.
I have an appointment with Meng Xiaoshan.
Tengo una cita con Meng Xiaoshan.
Meng Xiaoshan?
Meng Xiaoshan.
Forget it, then.
Pues, olvídalo.
Girl.
Hija.
Why are you leaving now?
¿Por qué te vas tan pronto?
I knew you were coming.
Sabía que vendrías hoy.
So I went to buy fish for you.
Te compré pescado.
We'll see.
Otra día.
Thank you.
Gracias a usted.
Girl, you...
Hija, tú...
Why don't you eat first before you leave?
¿Por qué no te vas después de comer?
Enough.
No hables tanto.
Are you okay?
¿Estás bien?
Are you hurt?
¿Estás herida?
I'm fine.
Estoy bien, estoy bien.
It's really broken here.
Realmente se rompió aquí.
Just repair it here.
Vamos a repararlo aquí.
Anyone? Come over here.
¿Alguien adentro puede venir?
Take the job.
A trabajar.
No need.
No hace falta.
I can fix it myself.
Voy a repararlo yo misma.
You can fix it here.
Sería mejor que lo reparemos aquí.
No need.
No hace falta.
Excuse me.
Disculpe, mueváse.
I have to reverse out.
Voy a retroceder.
Thank you.
Gracias.
There's no heater in your room.
¿No hay calefacción en tu habitación?
Your suitcase is expensive.
Esta maleta no es barata.
Your parents are so willing to
Tus padres
spend money on you.
tienen la voluntad de gastar mucho dinero para ti.
You have no conscience.
¡Qué cruel eres!
Go and do your homework.
Ve a hacer los deberes.
Waive the bill for that table.
Deja la comida de esa mesa ser gratis.
Apologize properly.
Pide perdón.
Hello, Gui Xiao.
Hola, Gui Xiao.
I'm hungry.
Tengo hambre.
Go to the lobby.
Ve al vestíbulo.
I need to take this call.
Tengo que contestar una llamada.
Gui Xiao, you sound like something's wrong.
Gui Xiao, tu voz se oye rara.
Did something happen at your home?
¿Pasó algo en casa?
Do you need money?
¿Quieres pedir dinero?
I'll send it to you.
Te lo llevo.
No.
No.
I'm just hungry.
Solo tengo hambre.
I haven't eaten since morning.
No he comido nada desde la mañana hasta ahora.
I was just passing by,
Justamente he pasado por aquí.
and I thought of
Recordaba que
you mentioned buying me a meal.
me invitarías a comer.
Where are you?
¿Dónde estás?
By the river.
Al lado del canal.
The river?
¿Canal?
Which entrance?
¿Cuál lado?
The intersection
Fuera del taller de la familia de Chen,
outside Lu Chen's factory.
ese cruce.
Are you here to pick me up?
¿Vienes a recogerme?
What are you doing? Put me down.
¿Qué haces? Bájame.
I have something urgent to do.
Tengo algo urgente que hacer.
How old are you?
¿Cuántos años tienes?
Aren't you afraid of hurting your back?
¿No tienes miedo de lastimarte la cintura?
Did you cry?
¿Lloraste?
No.
No.
I just feel
Solo un poco
a little down.
triste.
Because of Lu Chen, right?
¿Por Chen?
You two always came here for dating.
Ustedes dos solían tener cita por aquí.
Don't think I've forgotten.
No creas que lo he olvidado.
Let me take a guess.
Déjame adivinar.
You are upset
¿Por lo de Zhao Minshan y Chen
because of
te sientes
Lu Chen and Zhao Minshan.
mal?
Everyone knows
Todos los vecinos
about Zhao Minshan's divorce.
saben que Zhao Minshan se divorció.
She was embarrassed and anxious to get married again.
Su familia perdió la dignidad y tenía prisa por su segundo matrimonio.
But after years of hard efforts,
Pero después de varios años,
none of them can impress her.
no hubo nadie que le gustaba.
Finally,
Por fin esperó a Chen
Lu Chen has fallen into her lap.
que estaba soltero y necesitaba casarse.
So, a few days ago,
Por eso, hace unos días,
since she got engaged to Lu Chen,
desde que se comprometió con la familia de Chen
and received the betrothal gifts,
y recibió la dote,
she was desperate to hold a grand banquet
quería celebrar la boda de inmediato
immediately.
y de forma solemne.
She has invited all her acquaintances in the neighbourhood.
Han invitado a todos los conocidos que viven cerca.
You. How old are you?
¿Cuántos años tienes?
Still crying for your first love who has been ten years ago?
¿Por qué todavía lloraste por el primer amor de hace diez años?
Don't blame me for scolding you, Gui Xiao.
No me culpes por regañarte, Gui Xiao.
You thought you were still 18.
¿Aún crees que tienes 18 años?
There are many things you don't know.
Hay muchas cosas que no sabes.
When I told Haidong to break up,
Le dije a Haidong que rompimos,
we made it clean in the end.
ya rompimos totalmente.
You should have cried enough
Lo que deberías llorar,
when you broke up.
ya lloraste cuando rompieron.
Everyone has a first love.
¿Quién no tiene un primer amor?
If you keep thinking about your first love,
Si siempre piensas en tu primer amor,
how are you supposed to move on?
¿cómo podrás seguir tu vida?
I'm hungry.
Tengo hambre.
Okay, let's eat something delicious.
Bien, te llevaré a comer algo bueno.
The most delicious one.
Lo mejor.
Give me the car key.
Dame la llave del coche.
Where's your car?
¿Dónde está tu coche?
We're all acquaintances around here.
Tengo conocidos por aquí.
I'm not afraid of losing it.
No tengo miedo de perder.
I'll ask my husband
Dejaré a mi marido que venga más tarde
to drive it back.
y conduzca de vuelta.
It feels good.
Tiene buena textura.
I can switch with you if you want.
Si quieres conducirlo, cambiaré el coche contigo.
No need.
No hace falta.
You're already dying.
Ya estás tan triste.
How can I profit from your misfortunes?
¿Cómo puedo aprovecharme para pedirte esto?
Who's dying?
¿Quién está triste?